<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
	 xml:lang="en-US"
	 version="5.0">
  <info>
    <title>Author Guidelines for 8.5 x 11-inch Proceedings Manuscripts</title>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
        <personname>
          <firstname>Author-1</firstname>
          <surname>Name-1</surname>
        </personname>
        <affiliation>
          <orgname>Author Affiliation 1</orgname>
          <address><email>Author1@orgname.com</email></address>
        </affiliation>
      </author>
      <author>
        <personname>
          <firstname>Author-2</firstname>
          <surname>Name-2</surname>
        </personname>
        <affiliation>
          <orgname>Author Affiliation 2</orgname>
          <address><email>Author2@orgname.com</email></address>
        </affiliation>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <abstract>
      <title>Abstract</title>
      <para>
        The abstract is to be in fully-justified italicized text, at
        the top of the left-hand column as it is here, below the
        author information. Use the word “Abstract” as the title, in
        12-point Times, boldface type, centered relative to the
        column, initially capitalized. The abstract is to be in
        10-point, single-spaced type, and up to 150 words in
        length. Leave two blank lines after the abstract, then begin
        the main text.
      </para>
    </abstract>
  </info>
  
  <section xml:id="Section1">
    <title>Introduction</title>
    <para>
      All manuscripts must be in English. These guidelines include
      complete descriptions of the fonts, spacing, and related
      information for producing your proceedings manuscripts.
      Please follow them and if you have any questions, direct
      them to the production editor in charge of your proceedings
      at the IEEE Computer Society Press: Phone (714) 821-8380 or
    Fax (714) 761-1784.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section2">
    <title>Formatting your paper</title>
    <para>
      All printed material, including text, illustrations, and
      charts, must be kept within a print area of 6-1/2 inches
      (16.51 cm) wide by 8-7/8 inches (22.51 cm) high. Do not
      write or print anything outside the print area. All text
      must be in a two-column format.  Columns are to be 3-1/16
      inches (7.85 cm) wide, with a 3/8 inch (0.81 cm) space
      between them. Text must be fully justified.
    </para>
    <para>
      A format sheet with the margins and placement guides is
      available as both Word and PDF files as &lt;format.doc&gt;
      and &lt;format.pdf&gt;. It contains lines and boxes showing
      the margins and print areas. If you hold it and your printed
      page up to the light, you can easily check your margins to
      see if your print area fits within the space allowed.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section3">
    <title>Main title</title>
    <para>
      The main title (on the first page) should begin 1-3/8 inches
      (3.49 cm) from the top edge of the page, centered, and in
      Times 14-point, boldface type. Capitalize the first letter
      of nouns, pronouns, verbs, adjectives, and adverbs; do not
      capitalize articles, coordinate conjunctions, or
      prepositions (unless the title begins with such a word).
      Leave two 12-point blank lines after the title.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section4">
    <title>Author name(s) and affiliation(s)</title>
    <para>
      Author names and affiliations are to be centered beneath the
      title and printed in Times 12-point, non-boldface
      type. Multiple authors may be shown in a two- or
      three-column format, with their affiliations italicized and
      centered below their respective names. Include e-mail
      addresses if possible. Author information should be followed
      by two 12-point blank lines.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section5">
    <title>Second and following pages</title>
    <para>
      The second and following pages should begin 1.0 inch (2.54
      cm) from the top edge. On all pages, the bottom margin
      should be 1-1/8 inches (2.86 cm) from the bottom edge of the
      page for 8.5 x 11-inch paper; for A4 paper, approximately
      1-5/8 inches (4.13 cm) from the bottom edge of the page.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section6">
    <title>Type-style and fonts</title>
    <para>
      Wherever Times is specified, Times Roman or Times New Roman
      may be used. If neither is available on your word processor,
      please use the font closest in appearance to Times.  Avoid
      using bit-mapped fonts if possible. True-Type 1 fonts are
      preferred.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section7">
    <title>Main text</title>
    <para>
      Type your main text in 10-point Times, single-spaced. Do not
      use double-spacing. All paragraphs should be indented 1/4
      inch (approximately 0.5 cm). Be sure your text is fully
      justified—that is, flush left and flush right. Please do not
      place any additional blank lines between paragraphs.
    </para>
    <para>
      Figure and table captions should be 10-point boldface
      Helvetica (or a similar sans-serif font). Callouts should be
      9-point non-boldface Helvetica. Initially capitalize only
      the first word of each figure caption and table
      title. Figures and tables must be numbered separately. For
      example: “Figure 1. Database contexts”, “Table 1. Input
      data”. Figure captions are to be centered below the
      figures. Table titles are to be centered above the tables.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Figures and tables</title>
    <para>We will insert a figure into the file:</para>
    <figure>
      <title>Duck stamp</title>
      <mediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata scalefit="1"
                     align="center"
                     fileref="graphics/stamp200x128.gif"
                     format="GIF">
            <info>
              <orgname>O'Reilly &amp; Associates/Dover Archives</orgname>
            </info>
          </imagedata>
          
        </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    <para>
      Here is a formal table, set up with a width of 100%.
    </para>
    <table frame="all">
      <title>Table title</title>
      <?dbfo table-width="100%"?>
      <tgroup cols="3">
        <tbody>
          <row>
            <entry>a foo</entry>
            <entry>a bar</entry>
            <entry>a baz</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>b foo</entry>
            <entry>b bar</entry>
            <entry>b baz</entry>
          </row>
          <row>
            <entry>c foo</entry>
            <entry>c foo</entry>
            <entry>c baz</entry>
          </row>
        </tbody>
      </tgroup>
    </table>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section8">
    <title>First-order headings</title>
    <para>
      For example, “1. Introduction”, should be Times 12-point
      boldface, initially capitalized, flush left, with one blank
      line before, and one blank line after. Use a period (“.”)
      after the heading number, not a colon.
    </para>
    <section xml:id="Section81">
      <title>Second-order headings</title>
      <para>
        As in this heading, they should be Times 11-point
        boldface, initially capitalized, flush left, with one
        blank line before, and one after.
      </para>
      <section xml:id="Section811">
        <title>Third-order headings</title>
        <para>
          Third-order headings, as in this paragraph, are
          discouraged. However, if you must use them, use
          10-point Times, boldface, initially capitalized,
          flush left, preceded by one blank line, followed by
          a period and your text on the same line.
        </para>
        <para>
          Another paragraph under the 3rd order heading, just
          to be sure it works correctly.
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section9">
    <title>Footnotes</title>
    <para>
      Use footnotes sparingly (or not at all) and place them at
      the bottom of the column on the page on which they are
      referenced. Use Times 8-point type, single-spaced. To help
      your readers, avoid using footnotes
      <footnote>
        <para>
          Especially footnotes that are unnecessary, longer
          than strictly necessary, and written to be sure it
          is longer than one column width, like this
        one.</para>
      </footnote>
      altogether and include necessary peripheral observations in
      the text (within parentheses, if you prefer, as in this
      sentence).
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section10">
    <title>References</title>
    <para>
      List and number all bibliographical references in 9-point
      Times, single-spaced, at the end of your paper. When
      referenced in the text, enclose the citation number in
      square brackets, for example [1]. Where appropriate, include
      the name(s) of editors of referenced books.
      <footnote>
        <para>
          Here is a footnotes that are unnecessary, longer than
          strictly necessary, and written to be sure it is longer
          than one column width, like this one.
        </para>
      </footnote>
    </para>
    <bibliography>
      <biblioentry>
        <biblioset relation="article">
          <authorgroup>
            <author>
              <personname>
                <firstname>A.B.</firstname>
                <surname>Smith</surname>
              </personname>
            </author>
            <author>
              <personname>
                <firstname>C.D.</firstname>
                <surname>Jones</surname>
              </personname>
            </author>
            <author>
              <personname>
                <firstname>E.F.</firstname>
                <surname>Roberts</surname>
              </personname>
            </author>
          </authorgroup>
          <title>Article Title</title>
          <pubdate>Date</pubdate>
          <pagenums>1-10</pagenums>
        </biblioset>
        <biblioset relation="journal">
          <title>Journal</title>
          <publisher>
            <publishername>Publisher</publishername>
            <address>Location</address>
          </publisher>
        </biblioset>
      </biblioentry>
      <biblioentry>
        <authorgroup>
          <author>
            <personname>
              <firstname>A.B.</firstname>
              <surname>Smith</surname>
            </personname>
          </author>
          <author>
            <personname>
              <firstname>C.D.</firstname>
              <surname>Jones</surname>
            </personname>
          </author>
          <author>
            <personname>
              <firstname>E.F.</firstname>
              <surname>Roberts</surname>
            </personname>
          </author>
        </authorgroup>
        <title>Book Title</title>
        <publisher>
          <publishername>Publisher</publishername>
          <address>Location</address>
        </publisher>
        <pubdate>Date</pubdate>
      </biblioentry>
    </bibliography>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Section11">
    <title>Copyright forms and reprint orders</title>
    <para>
      You <emphasis role="strong">must</emphasis> include your
      fully-completed, signed IEEE copyright release form when you
      submit your paper. We must have this form before your paper
      can be published in the proceedings. The copyright form is
      available as a Word file, &lt;copyright.doc&gt;, as a PDF
      version, &lt;copyright.pdf&gt;, and as a text file in
      &lt;authguid.txt&gt;.
    </para>
    <para>
      Reprints may be ordered using the form provided as
      &lt;reprint.doc&gt; or &lt;reprint.pdf&gt;.
    </para>
  </section>
</article>
